OK then.
So for John 2,
like we have the this implementation in
IDMC.
First,
I'll walk you through the flow diagram.
OK, as part of batch,
there are so many like there are 5 to 6
phases in this ABC framework.
First is batch prerequisite,
batch preload prerequisite.
So this is like this.
This will check whether our in case of
our regular run,
it will check whether our June 2 batch
run,
latest June 2 batch run is completed or
not OK.
If it is completed then it will trigger
our actual batch task flow,
Actual June 2 batch task flow OK.
And if it is not completed,
it will just send out a notification
stating that the latest June 2,
June 2 batch run is not yet completed.
Please validate like that.
And if we want to run the task flow,
we have to run this batch with a task
flow.
We have to do it manually so we will have
the setup in the stone branch.
So we in IDMC we'll have two task flows,
1 is batch prerequisites task flow and
the other one is our actual zone 2 batch
task flow.
In the stone branch.
We will set a dependency for this 2 task
flow.
If the first one is completed
successfully,
then the second one will get triggered
and our zone 2 batch one get started.
If the first one is this failed,
then the second run,
the second task flow run won't start it.
So in case if we want to do a a manual
like if we want to run it after the
failure,
after the failure of the batch
prerequisite one,
we have to trigger it manually.
OK, if we are good,
I'll just move on to the next like actual
batch run and am I audible Hello yes yes
yes yeah yeah like please let me know if
you are not getting anything you you can
stop me and you can ask me so fast phase
in our join 2 batch is patch preload.
So it is it will be getting source name,
domain name, target zone,
application layer name as inputs.
Based upon these.
Using these values it will do a lookup on
the batch metadata table.
OK,
I think it's better to show you the data
model first.
So in ABC we are having metadata tables
and runtime tables.
We are having metadata metadata tables
like batch metadata, job metadata,
rule masters rule,
job rule assignment table and balance
reconciliation metadata and also we have
one other table ETL data ingestion
metadata table.
We have all these tables here.
So in LLD we have given all the tables
and columns description each and
everything we have provided.
So batch metadata table it is a static
table where we'll make static entries
into it about our batch details.
So like we will make a batch ID,
batch name and batch description,
e-mail ID, source name, domain name,
application name, application layer name,
application dependency name.
Like if we have any dependency,
if our zone 2 batch has any dependency on
zone 1 batch then we will provide that
dependency application name,
source name and also its corresponding
batch ID, name, the target zone,
all these things.
So OK and OK And we'll have other fields
like related to scheduling tool.
So these will be like updated based upon
the scheduling time in the stone branch
and also low frequency,
it will be daily for June 1 and it
depends on the source system also.
OK And then moving on to the geometry
data table, job metadata table,
here we will make entries for each table
which will be loaded as part of the batch
corresponding batch.
So here for example if we take broker
party address is being loaded under this
particular broker data domain batch then
we will make entry for that table OK
using this batch ID.
So I have made entry into the batch ID
table with the for example for with 48
batch with the 48 as my batch ID.
Then I will be using the same batch ID to
make entry for my broker party address
table into job metadata tables.
This job metadata table will just have
the details of our table.
Whatever the tables that we are that
we're gonna load under this batch run,
we will have all the table details which
can be used in the actual run and for
auditing purposes.
OK, we'll have all the details.
You can go through this document.
I can share this document with you.
This is not a tribute,
but this will be helpful for you to
understand the table structures better,
OK,
And then ETL data ingestion metadata
table,
this will store ETL ingestion
configuration details.
So OK,
so our zone 2 tables will have dependency
on the zone 1 tables right?
The zone 1 tables will act as source
tables for our target tables.
In order to have the list of source and
target tables,
we have this ETL data ingestion metadata
table.
So for example for my broker party
address table,
EDW party address T is my source table.
So in order to have that list of all the
source tables, we have this table.
So during that run,
in order to get the sourcing window based
upon the source table name,
we will be using this metadata table as
reference and we will make entries in the
actual runtime table to get the sourcing
window.
I'll tell you whenever that phase comes,
OK, next, moving in this job rule,
Job rule master table.
This is a catalog of column level
validation rules or whatever it will it
it,
it will have a distinct list of the DQ
checks.
So whatever the DQ checks that we want to
perform first,
we will we'll have to make entries into
this job metadata table.
Sorry, job rule master table.
OK,
so for example if we want to do a null
check then we will do.
We will have this rule entered into this
rule entry into this job related master
table and its corpus at the column level.
And these are just ordered columns.
When it is created like that,
I user ID and OK.
And if we are doing null check for any
other job in any other source system or
in any other batch,
we don't need to make another entry for
that particular job.
It is it acts like a distinct list of all
the dictionary checks that needs to be
performed across all batches in all jobs.
OK, and this is job rule assignment.
Whatever the rules that are defined in
the about table,
if we want to assign them to our
particular job then we will use this
table.
OK so here I want to do a null check for
my target table from a particular target
table.
So from a particular target table load,
we will have an entry into my job
metadata table, right?
So it will have a job ID, job ID.
So for the job ID I,
I will make an entry into this job
assignment table.
So this is my job ID 258 and this is my
rule ID.
So for null check we have the rule ID as
one.
So using this we we are assigning this
null check to this target caller.
OK.
If we want to assign any DQ checks which
are listed in the job rule master to our
table columns,
then we have to make entries into this
job rule assignment table.
OK, Then next,
moving on to the balance reconciliation
metadata.
If we have any balance reconciliation
checks or metrics that needs to be
performed in our job,
then we'll make entry into this balance
reconciliation metadata.
We have to provide the balancing type,
targetable details and column name and
also threshold type threshold value like
that.
OK,
this completes our metadata table
explanation.
If anyone has any question you can can
raise your hand.
OK,
I'll take that as no and moving on to the
runtime tables.
So these runtime tables will be making
use of the above metadata tables and
these will make entries into the runtime
tables during the process.
I'll explain the process and the flow,
but I'll give you a high level detail of
these runtime tables here.
So batch run start,
This is the runtime table for the batch
run which will have all the details
related to the batch run OK and Job run
stats.
This will have the details related to the
Job Run ETL Data Transition source window.
This will make use of the ETL Retangation
metadata table and it will retrieve the.
It will give us the sourcing window for
each and every source table.
So from here we will take the sourcing
window and we will fetch the data from
the actual source table in the actual
target table OK job error starts.
In case of any job failure,
we will make an entry into the job error
starts table kind of error Login OK Job
rule execution log.
So we have if we have any DQ checks we
will be making entries into the job rule,
Job rule, job rule assign table right?
So for each and every job rule assignment
we will have the log in this table.
So how many records got like.
So if we have 10 records coming from the
source and we have one rule assigned to
our to a particular column it will show
you the stat details like in case if the
if the particular rule assignment is
passed then it will give you the
execution details.
If the rule assignment got failed it will
give you the error message like that.
It will it will hold the high level.
It will hold the like execution details
for each job rule assignment OK and job
rule error detail table.
It will store each rules execution inputs
and outputs at column level OK and
balanced reconciliation set.
So for every balanced reconciliation we
made entries metric will make entries
into the job balanced cancellation
metadata table, right?
So it will give the stat details like
whether the metrics are out of balance,
out of threshold.
All those details will be there in this
balanced cancellation stats table.
Yeah, we're done with the runtime tables.
Also high level,
if you need any column level details,
all the details you can go through this
sample date,
column name and corresponding description
and the sample date.
OK.
Does anyone have any question here on
runtime tables?
So actually, yeah,
so job error statistics we have right
that table.
So we'll be reporting anywhere of those
records or which more in what was it not
like the error stats we have right.
So those details we'll be reporting to
someone like why it is error doubt.
So those kind of items will be yeah.
So mostly like whenever we make,
so if there is any failure that can be
captured in case of any network issue,
we won't be able to capture that.
Like we we won't be able to make an entry
into the job registers and notify someone
right, in case of network issue,
I'm saying.
But in any other scenario where the
execution is failed,
whenever any failure is happening,
we are marked we are whenever we are
making entry into this table,
we are make we are sending out a
notification stating that this particular
failure has happened during the job run.
Yeah, we are doing that.
Does this answer your question or is it
like, OK,
so this will be sent to admin team or?
Yeah that we have to figure out for now
we are as part of development we are
doing, we are, we are, we are giving,
we are sending out mails to our own mails.
Yeah, we have to check on this.
Usually it should be the someone like who
would be like taking care of the failures.
OK, fine.
OK.
Any more questions?
Yeah.
If not, I'm moving on to this flow, OK.
So here we will be passing source name,
domain name in the batch preload.
I'm I'm starting with the batch preload.
So this is the first step in our actual
zone to batch run.
So here there will be passing source name,
domain name, target zone,
application layer name.
So this batch preload phase we will be
sending out all these values using a
static parameter file.
So using these values we will it will do
a lookup on the batch metadata table and
fetch the batch ID and also batch run OK.
And using the batch ID it will do a
lookup on the batch run stats table and
it will fetch the latest status and batch
rerun flag OK if the batch rerun flag is
north.
And if the latest batch run status is
either failed or started,
then if it is started,
it will it will it will update the status
to fail and it will make a new and new
entry into the batch run starts table
with the same execution run ID and with
status start OK.
If it is failed then it will make an
entry into new entry into the batch run
starts table.
So it's a kind of restart scenario in
case if the if the batch batch read and
flag is in and if there is no prior entry
or if the previous status is already
started.
If if the batch rerun flag is N,
then there will there it can be new or
rerun scenario.
OK.
So if the if my previous batch rerun flag
is N and status is completed,
that means it's a regular scenario
wherein we'll just we'll just make a new
entry.
Yeah.
But is yes, no, OK,
it will be a regular scenario where we'll
just make a new entry for our new run and
batch run strats with new execution run
ID which status has started and we will
pass the execution type as new in case if
it is failed or started,
then it is our restart scenario.
So if it is already started,
if it if my previous entry is in starter
state,
we'll just update it to fail and make a
new entry with starter status.
If it is failed,
then we'll just make a new entry with
status as started with the same execution
run ID.
In case of restart,
we will be use the same execution run ID
as that of the previous run.
OK and we will pass the execution type as
restart OK if my batch rerun flag is not
equal to north,
that means if it is Y or ZY represent
zone 2 rerun, Z represents zone 1 rerun.
OK in case of zone 1 rerun or zone 2
rerun,
we have to make a manual entry into the
batch run stats table with status started
OK And in that case like we will pass the
execution type as rerun if my batch rerun
flag equal to Y otherwise we will pass
the execution type as Z1 rerun if my
batch return flag equal to C OK,
we'll pass batch ID execution run ID
execution type and to the next phase that
is job reload OK.
This will have like here it will get
inputs.
It will take inputs like job name,
batch ID execution and ID execution type.
And if we have any stage table,
we are just keeping the stage table
record point at 0 initially if we have
any.
I'll tell you why we are considering the
stage table record count here in this
space.
Is everyone clear with the batch preload
process?
Yeah.
Can some someone respond if it's clear?
Clear.
Yes, yes, sure.
Yeah, yeah.
OK.
So next in the job failure process,
it will take the input as job name and
batch ID.
So using the job name and batch ID,
it will fetch the job ID from the job
metadata table, OK.
And and it will also check whether the
exact flag is Y or not.
Basically,
I he's had to flag with this indicates
whether the high record is active or not
in that particular table.
OK.
And also based on the job ID from the job
metadata table, it will,
it will take the latest job,
latest job run details from the job run
stats table, OK, link statuses like that.
OK,
it will take that and using the execution
run,
run type taking like getting from this
batch preload process.
If it is restart,
if it is not restart then it will be
either new or rerun or zone 1 rerun
scenario.
OK, if it is new,
let's say like if it is new or rerun or
zone 1,
rerun the processing first let's cover
new scenario.
That means strictly scenario.
In case of regular scenario,
our previous like previous status would
be completed, correct?
In case of new scenario.
And we will also consider the execution
run ID.
OK Here execution run ID concept will
come in the restart scenario.
For for example, for now,
let's say in case of a regular scenario,
let's say Azure,
if my previous batch run has completely
successful,
then in the next day the run would be new.
It's just like a new scenario.
In that case,
we'll just make a new entry into the job
run status table with new execution run
ID with status as started OK and then
into the batch in into the job and stats
table.
Next.
Next we will make an entry into the ETL
data ingestion source window which will
provide the sourcing window for our
actual table load OK.
In case of new load,
based upon the job ID and batch ID,
it will do a look up on the ETL data
ingestion metadata table and job run test
table to create entries into this ETL
data injection source window table.
So here in June 1,
June 1 batch will be like they're marking,
they're having four state,
four kind of statuses in their batch run.
First one would be started, completed,
failed partial.
So the our zone 2 batch run will get
started if if if my dependent zone 1
batch is either in completed or partial
state.
What does this partial meaning completed
meaning?
If all the jobs under that particular
zone 1 batch is completed then it will
hold the status as completed.
If few of the jobs in the zone under the
zone 1 batch is completed and few have
failed then it will take the status as
partial.
Our zone 2 batch will get started if few
of the jobs job loss are completed.
OK,
so in that case we have to get the
sourcing window for each and every table
and we should not proceed with the tables
table loads whose sources or whose source
loads are failed in the zone 1 batch run,
correct?
So for that purpose,
this particular detailed data injection
source window table is introduced which
will have the source level details.
So for each and every source level
details and for each and every source we
will have the corresponding sourcing
window,
sourcing startup and sourcing enter.
Hope everyone is getting.
I'm just giving this because this is not
is dedicated to June,
June 2 and June 3 OK.
In case of new load we will just make use
of job ID and batch ID and we will fetch
the source table names and using the
source table name we will get the latest
job run details of that particular source
table.
Using those we will make entries into the
ETL data ETL data ingestion source window
table OK and then we will check if if my
source job status is not equal to fail
for the current job.
So once we make entries into that,
we will check whether all the like if my
target table has 222 source tables,
if any one of the source table load is
failed, I should not proceed further.
I should not do the load for my target.
So that is what here it is meaning.
So if any of the source gets failed, we,
we, we just yeah, if I, if I, if we,
if anything is getting failed,
we just mark the status,
whatever the entry that we have made here
in the job run stats, right?
We'll just mark it as failed.
And we will create one entry in job at a
stats table because we have to make an
error log, right?
And then we will send out a failure
notification stating that the source job
run has been failed for this particular
table.
That is the reason why we are not
proceeding further.
We are failing the job here.
Got it.
If we are good,
let me know if everyone is clear here.
Yes, yes.
OK,
then and then moving on to the next step.
Here we will check whether if there are
any DQ checks assigned to our particular
job.
If S,
then we will make entries into the job
role execution log table with the job run
ID,
job role assignment ID and status as
started.
If there are no,
then we'll just go to this step end step,
OK.
And in case of zone 1 rerun or normal
zone 2 rerun then also the scenario would
be the same.
It will just make a new entry.
In case of rerun whatever the table that
are that are loaded complete that are
loaded successfully in my previous run,
those will also be loaded again in case
of rerun OK zone to rerun not zone 1
rerun zone right?
In case of even in zone 1 rerun all the
tables will be loaded OK zone 1.
The concept of zone 1 rerun will be
explained like will be more of functional
side.
Like in case of any we will have a column
called zone one UUID.
So in case of zone 1 rerun we will just
update that column.
So that functionality will be explained
as part of the actual table load.
OK,
so in case of zone 1 rerun also we'll
make a new entry for each and every
target table with status has started into
the job transfers preload.
And in case of zone 1 rerun,
we will the process will be similar to
the new load.
But in case of zone 2 rerun we have to
because.
So for example in case of zone 2 rerun,
we it would be a scenario like this.
I triggered my job today in the morning
like it got triggered in the scheduling
tool automatically it got failed.
So upon validation,
we got to know that there's some issue
with the logic and we have to do the run
from day one to day 10, like till date,
OK, today's 10th, right?
So my,
whatever the data that has been loaded on
from June 1st to June 10th should be
reloaded.
So we're doing a rerun here for June 2.
No,
in that case we have to mention we have
to provide the execution run ID of the
batch run or the of the batch run which
which is which is there in the first day
one.
So it will take the sourcing start time
from that from that execution to tail up
like A2 tail like the job and time of the
source.
So here in case of read and don't to read
and we it will do a look up on the same
table data ingestion table to get the
details based on the minimum execution
run ID and latest successful executed
zone to job load.
It will take all these details and it
will bring the sourcing statum and
sourcing end time for a particular table
load.
And before this rerun the cleanup should
be happened manually.
OK,
Hope everyone is clear here between rerun
and June 1 rerun here.
We don't do anything now and this we will
do our cleanup.
It should be done manually.
OK, OK.
Yeah.
In case of any reruns also the process
would be same.
If any of the job still it shows job cost
failed.
I will just send out a notification
mostly here.
It won't take it won't be like it won't
get the scenario because we are taking
the end sourcing end time from the latest
completed June to job, right?
If it is in completed state,
then we won't get a a scenario like
wherein we'll have this.
So in case of new and June 1 rerun,
we would expect that the source job
status might be failed in case of that
failed and notification will be signed
off failing the job.
OK.
And we are good with this new region and
Zone 1 rerun scenarios.
Now coming on to the restart scenario.
Hello, yes, Ishwari,
is there any script which is doing the
cleanup or how Currently we don't have
any script for OK,
we're manually deleting for the cleanup.
So here for rerun cleanup,
there are a process already are already
aligned.
We have the process already aligned.
You can check with the Swayam or Saurabh
on the rerun thing because it is it is a
different topic.
It, it is not related to ABC.
It is so more of is it something which
has been like designed or developed in
the IDMC, right?
No, no, no, it's just normal cleanup.
But the cleanup steps are already as far
as I remember those are already we have
the all the steps.
You can check with Saurabh or Swayam on
this T run cleanup Zone 1 read Zone 2
read and cleanup.
You can check with them.
OK, you got it.
This is not related to ABC.
OK, That is a reason, right?
Those details are not mentioned here.
Even I'm not short on the steps.
OK, OK got it.
OK and in case of restart it will handle
manually.
It will be handled automatically in the
code in case of restart.
Restart is mostly happens whenever any
network issue happens.
OK,
because of that our of our job run got
interrupted and we are going ahead with
the restart.
Then clean up will be handled
automatically within the code.
In case of free run,
it should be manually done and that we
have to get it from someone.
Saurabh works fine.
OK and coming to this coming back to this
job preload, in case of restart,
it will check if this latest state status
is either started or failed.
If it is not started or failed,
then it would be completed.
So we'll skip the job run.
So in case of any network issue,
if out of my like let us assume there are
10 tables under the under a particular
batch run.
So out of this 10 tables,
my 8 tables got loaded successfully.
During my 9th table run,
it got interrupted due to some network
issue and then I like and and then we
decided to do our restart.
During restart we'll we can directly
trigger our zone to batch task flow.
We don't need to trigger the batch free
requisite.
We can directly do a run from here OK or
direct.
We can directly trigger a batch task flow
from stone branch OK.
And then if my job run has been completed
in my previous run,
then its previous status would be started
with would be completed.
So in case of restart,
we would be using the same execution run
ID.
OK,
if for the same whatever the execution
run ID that has been used for the current
run.
If it is same as the previous run and
it's and if its status is completed,
then we are skipping that run.
OK, you're getting my point right.
I I just want to,
I just want to be clear on restart,
completed previous status with completed
status and rerun with previous status as
completed.
So in case of restart,
we would be checking whether the we we
will be using the same execution run ID.
In case of restart OK,
whatever the execution run ID that has
been used in the previous run,
we would be using the same 1.
So we would be checking whether the
previous status is completed and the
execution run ID is also same.
In that case we are skipping the job run.
In case of free run,
if my previous status is completed and
execution run IDs are different then I
have to do the load again.
OK,
I'm just moving here just to make sure
that you are clear on this part.
So in case of restart.
So here we are passing the execution type
as restart.
Here we are doing the entry with the same
execution run ID.
Here also we are doing the entry into
this table with the same execution right.
Execution run ID is the column in batch
run stats table.
OK hope you are clear here.
Hello, yes, yes, OK, yes, sure.
So coming back to this job preload here,
whenever we have completed,
we are just skipping the run.
And for the ones which are having the
fail or started status, the OK,
if we have failed,
then we are just updating the status in
the job run starts to started.
That's it.
We, we're, we just want, we,
we're trying to use the same entry even
for the current run.
We're just updating the status from
failed to started.
If it is already started,
we are using this as it is.
We are not making anything OK.
And in case if it is started,
that means mostly it would be due to
previous trans network failure, OK?
Because because of that it won't be able
to update the status to failed.
OK.
That is the reason why we we might not be
able to make an entry into the job error
stats right earlier.
That is the reason why we are making an
entry into the job error stats for the
previous runs.
Abrupt failure OK, OK.
And after that for restart,
we will create entries in the error.
This is similar to this new load.
So it will make use of job ID and batch
ID.
It will bring all the source stable
details and based upon the source table
details,
it will get the job job run details of
each and every source table and it will
make entries into the ETL data transition
source window table.
OK.
I think it's better to add this source in
it.
Yes, OK if here, here.
One more thing like if, if,
if there are entries already created into
this table in my previous run,
it will skip the IT will skip making the
entries OK, else it will do you want it.
It will, it won't do.
It won't like the entries are.
If the entries are already made into this
table in the previous run,
it won't do it again.
I just want to add that failure 1 here,
this one here also will be here.
Also we'll check whether all the source
tables or source table runs or computers
successfully or not.
If all the source tables are completed
then only it will move forward otherwise
otherwise it will just update the status
in the job run stats.
It will update the status in the job
stats has failed and creates one entry in
the job error stats and it will send out
a notification stating that source job
run has been failed and that is the
reason why we are failing the target
table run also and then saying it will it
will do check for if there are any
statistics.
If S it will make an entrance into the
job error job rule execution log table
else it will just go on to this step.
So it will perform a clean up of the
target table.
In case of restart it will be doing it
here automatically using this step and
after that if we have any stage table.
In between our source and target table,
it will check whether the source table is
loaded as part of my previous run.
It will check the count of the records.
So we are doing a full PDO for our table
load.
So in case of full PDO either all either
all the requests will just loaded
otherwise none will be loaded in this in
the run in the current load like whatever
the in in a particular load.
So if my stage table count is greater
than 0 that means my stable my stage
table got loaded in my previous run.
So in case of restart we won't be able to
do like we we are not going to load our
stage table again.
We're just skipping that load so far that
here we are doing a count.
We are getting the count in case if we
don't have stage table or if like we we
are just assigning the stage table record
value as zero like all the all the tables
doesn't have stage table right in that
case and that we are just keeping it as 0.
OK on a high level like in job preload we
are doing three things.
Making entry into job run stats,
making entries into ETL data ingestion
source window,
making entries into job role execution
log.
In case of restart we are doing a clean
up checking whether the stage stable load
is stage stable is loaded in my previous
or not.
In a high level,
this is what happening in the job reload.
Let me know if if anyone has any
questions on this job load phase.
I think we are good.
We are good.
OK OK,
so here from this step we will be passing
the job run, LD stage table record count,
sourcing dates to the next steps and we
will we are we are exiting this phase.
OK so here in this phase first it will
check whether the stage table count is 0
if it is yes.
If it is S that means stage table is not
loaded in my previous run.
OK,
so then it will fetch the data from the
source table using the sourcing window,
OK,
using the sourcing start time and
sourcing.
And for incremental load,
we need the sourcing and strike sourcing
data strike.
So it will just fetch the records.
So it will do multiple things.
OK in this mapping,
in this source to stage load mapping,
it will do multiple things.
One is it will load,
it will fetch the records from the source
using sourcing window and load it into
stage table.
OK.
And if there are any DQ checks in the
same mapping, if there are any DQ checks,
it will perform the DQ validation.
If there are like there will be.
There are two kinds of DQ checks,
one is critical and the other one is
informational.
In case of any critical checks failure,
we will route those records into error
detail table and we don't route them into
target in case of any informational
checks.
That means as a name suggests,
if it's just like if if anything went
wrong with any columns data then we just
need information it can be loaded into
target.
So in case of information we will load
the record into both tables.
One is added table and the other one is
the targeted.
Why we are loading it into error data
table?
Because we we we need to notify the team
when you when you notify them right
regarding this failure, DQ check failure.
That's the reason why we are routing into
the error detail table.
OK,
this is related to the DQ checks and in
the job run stress temple.
So here I have given all temp,
temp temp tables right?
So we have all the zone 2 target table
set up in Snowflake whereas ABC tables in
our postgrad sequel.
If we have target tables and if we have
table source and target tables from
different database, full PDO doesn't work.
In order to enable full PDO,
we're trying to make that database same.
That is the reason why we have created
some temporary tables in Snowflake in
temporary ABC tables in Snowflake to
capture the source related information
into the ABC tables.
And then we we will use these tables in
our post load and we will update all the
source target all the run details in our
actual order tables only.
OK,
so here after this job will add a
detailed timetable.
We have job run starts timetable wherein
we are we will be capturing the source
record count and target unchanged record
count.
So whatever the table,
so whatever the source record count that
we whatever that records that are fetched
from the source out of the source
qualifier, source transformation,
we are just counting that and we are
making that entry into this step and also
target and change records whatever that
records for which there is no change,
we would be ignoring them, right.
So those record also we are capturing
here only.
And after that balance sheet cancellation,
if we have any balance reconciliation
metrics for the for the particular source
column or like whatever,
we will perform those calculations on the
source columns in this only.
And we will make an entry of all these
source balance metric values into this
balance reconciliation stats timetable
and are referential integrated.
But so if our target table has any parent
table for which so we you know
differential integrity, right?
So it's like a parent chain, parent chain.
So we got a ID column into the target
table for which we don't find an entering
the parent table then it is called array
record.
So that array record will be routed into
the RA table array timetable here OK.
If there are no records in the stage
table then all these will be work on.
Once the stage table is loaded,
the data will be loaded from the stage to
target table OK.
If there are any records in the stage
table for this particular current job run
ID then it will skip the stage table load.
It will skip all these things.
It will directly go to this stage to
target table load.
OK and OK.
If you're good with the job load I'll we
can move on to the job post load.
If if anyone has any questions here
please let me know I'll be good.
Yes, OK, then in my job post loads,
in my job post load,
if my like target table load is completed
successfully, then what will happen?
First we will load the RA records which
are loaded here.
Right here we have routed our RA tables
into time bar.
So we'll just load those time bar tables
into the main RA table and then we'll
check if there are any DQ checks.
Then we will load whatever the error
records that are loaded here into the job
rule error detail time.
We will load those error records from the
job rule error detail time to actual job
rule error table In Aurora and even in
Snowflake,
we have job rule error detail table.
It's a permanent table in both,
in both areas.
So this will hold the details at the
record column level.
So for every record,
I'll tell you the difference between the
job role table and job role execution log
table.
So in job role execution log table,
we will make entries into this table for
each and every job role assignment made
in the job role assignment metadata table.
OK in job role array data table,
how we will do for every lattice issue we
have two checks, two call.
We have two DQ checks on 22 columns.
So for a record that is coming from the
source, if there are two like 2 columns,
we have defined 2 DQ checks on 2 columns
right?
Both are failed.
So then in that case we will have two
entries into the job role error detail
table one for first column and the second
one for second call.
So it will be have it will be at column
record column level.
So for each and every record how many if
what is the issue for that particular
column.
So all those details will be there.
How it is called?
How how how is the column looking like?
All that description would be there in
the job role error detail tree.
OK,
so for these particular two job rule
assignment,
we'll have two entries into the job rule
execution log table.
So they in the job rule execution table
in total,
in total how many source records got
failed this how many source records are
failed for this particular DQ check for
this particular job in total it will
calculate and it will show the error
error messages or execution messages for
this particular job lesson table OK.
So once this is done,
we will check if there are ones.
So first whatever the error records that
are present in the job rule error detail
stamp table,
it will be loaded into the actual job
rule error detail table and then it will
check if there are any error records in
the job rule.
If there are any,
then it will update the error message and
status as failed.
In the job rule execution lock table
there are no record then it will update
the execution latest and status is passed
on the job rule execution lock tape.
Hope you got the difference between job
rule and job rule execution update.
If not please switch OK OK then if and
then late next step is it will check if
there are any balancing metrics that are
sent to my job or not.
If else like if there are no DQ checks,
it will just bypass this OK.
If there are no balance checks,
it will just bypass all these steps and
it will go here OK.
If there are any balance checks OK,
it will fetch the source balancing metric.
So we have populated source related
balancing metric values into balance
reconciliation stats STEM table here in
the job load right here.
So whatever the entries that we have made
are related to source balance metrics,
it will fetch all those from right and
also based upon the target table details
and column details it will do a balancing.
It will calculate all the target related
balancing metrics and it will compare
both of them as a out of balance value.
It will do a out of balance check if both
out of balance is nothing,
but it will take the difference of source
and target balancing metrics if out of
balance value is 0.
So whatever that records that are
intended to be loaded from source,
those sum,
aggregated sum and this target aggregate
sum like if it is ample,
we'll do some of a discount column,
we will do a count, OK.
So it will check whether the source and
target difference between source and
target values.
It will calculate this difference between
source and target metric values.
We we are we are taking that difference
as out of balance.
If the out of balance is 0 then it will
update the balance in flag is Y and
within threshold flag is Y in the balance
reconciliation stats table.
If it is not,
then it will update the balance
reconciliation as N in and then it will
check that out of balance value out of
the difference that we got against the
threshold value provided in the balanced
translation metadata table.
OK if if it is within the threshold.
If it is less than the threshold,
then it will update the threshold flag as
Y if the out of balance value is less
than if it is less than the threshold
value in balanced translation.
Otherwise it will update it as I OK
update the balance reconciliation check
status in job.
So we have a flag called balance
reconciliation check.
We we are going to update this this flag
in the in the next steps.
So and the next steps OK,
like we will update that flag,
ball Recon flag,
whatever mentioned in the job run stats,
preload, job run stats table,
we will update it as Y if my,
if my source and target records are
within threshold, OK,
either if it is out of balance or within
balance, it should be within threshold.
If they are within threshold,
we will mark it directly as Y,
otherwise N If there are no balancing
metrics, we will update it as X OK,
then it will fetch the source record
count.
There are no balance metrics to be
performed.
When I Recon check flag will be it's.
It's not status, it's for flag.
OK,
after that we have populated source
record count and target and change record
count into a temporary job run stable,
right?
We will fetch those two values and we
will also calculate target,
insert record count,
target operate record count,
target array record count,
critical array record count.
All these things we will do and we'll
update the corresponding columns in the
job run search table.
We will check whether the source record
count and target record count.
So source record count will be will be
compared against the sum of target record
counts.
OK,
like source target insert record count
place, target update record place,
What is this critical error record count
place?
What else are a record count?
All these sum aggregated sum will be
compared against the social code.
If both are matching then we will update
the record account balancing flag as Y in
the operand stats as it would be N.
And for a given job run ID,
we will check the status of record count
balance flag, critical error check flag,
informational error check flag,
balance reconciliation check flag in job
run stats.
OK,
we will decide the final status of final
status that needs to be populated into
the job table using all these criteria.
First one is record count balancing flag
which will check whether the source and
target record counts or imbalance or not.
Second one is critical error check flag
if there are any critical error records
that means if there are any source
records which fail the critical DQ check
that is assigned to our job then our then
this critical error check flag would be N
and say if or if there are no critical
error records then it would be Y and
coming to informational error flag.
So if there are any informational error
records then it would be N else it would
be Y and boundary construction flag.
I have already mentioned this.
So this would be why if all the balancing
metrics are within threshold and it would
be end OK.
So in case if any one of the following
happens that means if my if my record
count balancing flag equal to north or if
there any critical validation check fails
or if there any balancing metrics that
are out of threshold then my job run
status would be failed and a entry would
be made into the job error stats table
and I have failure notification would be
sent out.
OK this is 1 case and the second case if
any of the informational DQ checks fail
and if any of the balancing metrics are
out of balance but within threshold,
status of the job run would be completed
but and warning notification would be
signed out stating that there are some
information error records.
And also there are some balancing metrics
which are out of balance but within
threshold like that information would be
sent out.
And 3rd case if my record count balancing
flag equal to Y and if there if if all
the critical and informational checks are
passed and if all the balancing metrics
are balanced are completely balanced then
my status of my job would be completed
and SXS notification would be sent out.
Does anyone have any question on this job
post load part?
Oh yeah.
So one question is,
was it mandated to have DQ checks and
balance metrics checks for all the no,
it's not mandatory.
That's why we are bypassing them, right.
If we don't have any balance checks,
we are bypass.
So if we if we don't have any DQ checks,
we are bypassing all these things.
And even in the preload if you see if we
don't have any DQ checks,
we are bypassing like we're not making
entries into this thing,
we're bypassing them.
OK, we're also we're bypassing.
Look for critical error checks as well,
right?
Whatever, like whatever.
Yeah, whatever.
Like if we don't have DQ checks,
we don't make entries in the preload into
this double execution log type here we
will bypass.
And in the actual job load,
we won't do this all these checks if we
don't have DQ checks.
And in the post load,
if we don't have DQ checks,
we will bypass.
We don't do this job load or job will
execution load,
we'll bypass and we don't have balance
reconciliation as balance reconciliation
happens in job load, we won't do this.
And in the post load, we won't do this.
All this calculation, we will don't this,
we'll just bypass and we'll just go to
the job run service.
OK,
in case if my this is related to job post
load success,
I think it's better to keep like this
maybe I'm thinking but I'll check this
file if it is.
If the job is successful then this will
happen.
If the job it's failed.
Now what it will do?
It will just update the entries whatever.
I'm assuming my job is having dicky
checks.
So if there are any Dicky checks,
if there are any entries that are made in
in the pre in the preload step,
job preload step,
we will just mark them as failed, OK?
We'll just mark them as failed.
And what are the entry that is made into
the job run stacks?
We'll just update it as a failed, OK?
That is not added here because we are
planning.
We are having this Lucid primarily for a
successful run,
otherwise successful targetable load.
OK, OK, once this is completed,
we'll have batch.
So under batch we'll have multiple jobs.
So here in the batch post load,
it will check if all the job loads are
completed successfully.
If S then it will update the status in
the batch table as completed and S
success notification will be sent out.
OK here also a notification will be sent
out.
Success notification will be sent out
here.
If any one of the table job load gets
failed then the status in the job branch
starts will be failed and a filed
notification will be sent out.
That's it.
This is the process actual flow of ABC.
So all the like component level like all
the IDMC components related to this
particular ABC are available under common
ABC folder in IDMC DAA common.
I guess let me open.
Sorry like is everyone good with this
flow?
If anyone has any questions please let me
know.
Meanwhile, I'll just open this IDMC.
DA common.
So if you see DA common and this we'll
have ABC.
So you have all the components related to
the RABC here, OK.
And for testing purposes,
we have used broker party address table
job task flow and we have created a batch
task flow for broker which is under this
broker.
And you should not run the task flow like
if POC is happening if you want to like
just even just to see like you can check
with the Bharat is out.
So this is the batch task flow.
So this is the batch task.
This is our batch task.
This you'll have this is batch preload
and this is actual table load.
And in case it will just do that
calculation if if this gets failed,
it will be mark the error count as one.
If error count is greater than 0,
it will update the status as failure.
Otherwise,
access this status will be sent to this
batch post load where it will just update
the status based upon the status batch
status not fiction failure,
not fiction will be sent out here.
OK,
let me open the job load job task flow.
So there is this is the job task flow.
This is job preload.
So in case if any,
any component fails in the job post loop,
so it will it will do this,
it will this will be triggered job reload
failure wherein like if any entries are
made into this execution log double it,
we will mark them as failed.
If any entry like whatever the entry that
is made in the job run stacks will be
marked as failure.
If if there is any issue happened during
the job runs that's entry itself then it
will send out a notification directly
here only.
So if this component like where we are
making an entry into job run stress if it
if it gets failed will directly send out
a notification and it will fail the task
flow.
In case if this task flow gets failed
here,
that means this subtask flow gets failed.
You know,
so it will it will fail this task flow,
this job level task flow stating that
that's that this particular job process
preload has failed.
And it will give you the workflow name
also in the failure message and with the
notification is already sent in the job
preload password itself.
So it will just fail this task flow.
That's it.
OK and as part of testing you have to I
think we like these things has to be
covered like testing each and every
component.
Is it giving a proper notification or not
in case if anything is failing?
OK,
this is like in case of restart and if my
job run is completed in the previous run,
we have to skip that run, right?
For that purpose,
we have this decision task.
So in case of rerun restart,
it will directly go to the end step.
It won't do anything, it won't do,
it won't do any load anything even it
gets skipped.
It will skip even the entries into the
job execution log, job error,
stats transition,
everything will be skipped here in job
cleaner task flows.
So here it will check if, if,
if it is completed and if the isolation
tab is also restart, then it will skip.
See, it won't do anything.
It will just go to end.
First line will just go to end.
That's it.
OK and then if my stage load in case of
free start,
if my stage table is already loaded we
are just skipping the stage load and
moving on to the actual stage 2 target
table load.
If it is not loaded in the free steps
then we are uploading it,
then we are loading the stage table and
then we are doing this.
So in case if any of these loads has
failed with some execution error,
this post load failure will be triggered.
Here it is doing the same thing if there
are any records and here it will check I
told you no OK it will.
It will just check if there if there if
there are any DQ checks,
it will check if there are any records in
this table.
If there are any requests,
it will delete it.
And what are the entry that's made into
the table,
it will just mark it as failure and it
will send a failure notification OK.
If this task flow gets failed then it
this notification will fix OK and once
the target table load gets filled and job
post for success,
this is nothing but like this RA,
balance sheet cancellation everything.
So first our temporary 2 main RA will be
happened.
Then if if the DQ check indicator is wide
then we will do the array detail and draw
approval execution.
If there are no decay,
we'll just bypass step.
If there are balance checks then we'll do
balance reconstruction.
Otherwise we can just pipe this step.
If we have then we'll we will process
post load success based upon the post
load success failure success.
Like based upon the status updated in the
job and sets table,
we will send out a notification.
If the status is failed then we'll fail
this task.
OK, that's it.
This is the actual batch transflow and
let me show you the batch data present as
well.
So for every domain,
they're having a separate ABC folder.
So they have to like the all the ABC
components are present in the DA common
ABC folder.
For every domain they have to take the
copy from there and paste like take the
take the copy of all the components and
paste it here.
Let me show you badge pray requisite.
I think here it is badge pray requisite.
This is the batch play requisite task
flow wherein test it will just check the
latest zone to add status.
This framework is same for June 2 and
June 3 right?
That's why I have just given target zone.
If it is loading from in June 3 then it
will take it will check the latest zone 3
batch status.
If it is completed then it will just.
If it is completed then the task flow
will be just completed successfully if it
is failed if it if it is have.
If it is other than started,
it will just send out a notification here
and it will fail the task flow if we have
any execution.
If there is any execution error,
we are just failing the last flow.
We can also send out a notification
stating that this particular execution
got failed.
Anyway,
it is fine like it is just checking the
status, right?
But if I upgrade this,
I'll just send out a mail.
OK, Is everyone OK with the details?
And if you want anything else,
you can ask me now.
No, no, we are good usually.
OK.
And I also shared the test cases also,
right?
If any other,
if you feel that any other test cases
needs to be added,
I think you will do each and every test
case, right?
Like checking each and every component
failure, everything.
I hope everything would be covered.
And yeah, yes, OK,
I have just shared only the test cases
that we have performed as part of
development.
OK, Actually those were very high level.
So we needed the architecture and the
table level details also so that we could
include that as well in our test cases.
So that's why we wanted to understand the
architecture.
Like now we've got we've got it like what
to add, what needs to be added.
And also I just want to say because here
we have not like each and everything has
failed and proper notificial should be
sent out like that.
Also I think it it would be better if we
add those texts.
Yes,
yes in Aurora we have ABC tables
currently in default DB ABC metadata
tables.
OK these are the tables.
But someone was saying like I,
I heard that we will be having a new
database set up for ABC tables in order
we'll we are checking on it.
If we get any information we'll pass on.
OK, sure hope we are good.
And if you're asking like do you know how
to raise the access for IDMC like are you
aware of the process?
I think it please part of our initial
access,
we'll we'll have one document to raise
all the access initially, right.
I think it is OK part of our only of our
of that access document only if you want
I can share that.
I'll, I'll check, I'll check with them.
If you have that detail,
please share it with us or else like let
us know if we can connect with anyone
else for that, maybe sort of or anyone.
Yeah.
But if you have the details,
please share it with us.
Yeah, sure.
And I just want to add, yeah, here.
So one thing is if we get any new setup
of APC tables in Aurora,
that is one thing pending we need to
check and even the in the Snowflake we
are having ABC timetables, right.
So they're planning to have those
timetables for each and every domain
specific schema.
So for each and every broker domain,
they'll have a schema ABC and under which
they'll have this timetables are a tables
like that.
So that is had to be like had to be like
designed in the Snowflake.
OK,
but far now we are just we're just
pointing to the testing schema temp
tables.
OK,
that is on the point and also the pending
design items in ABC's we're to align on
the history historical or catch upload.
So whether we need to do entries into the
ABC data tables for auditing purpose and
also first time incremental.
So for the first time when we are so
historical and catch upload would be from
Teradata to Snowflake but the first time
in incremental would be from zone one,
zone 2 OK though.
So we are at to align on this design
areas.
These are edge scenarios.
Nothing would be like affected with this,
but yeah, these are the open items.
I just wanted to let you know so that
once these are completed,
we will info once the touching is done
from our end,
you can also touch the scenarios.
OK.
I think I think we are good.
I have covered almost everything.
I I yes, Yes, I can.
Yes.
Issue.
Yeah.
I'll stop the recording.
Yeah.
OK.
Sandhya Rani.
Like, yeah, yeah, like you can.
You can stop there, correct?